#你看 上次我撿的這個流浪貓 (註︰不直譯「上次」，因為好像有點奇怪，感覺英文的"pick"是地方拾起來的意思，所以改了用"Adopt)
Look! These are the stray cats that I adopted previously.
#不是流浪貓哦
They're not exactly stray cats in fact.
#應該是那個
I think they were,
#那個母的不要它們啦 哦
they were abandoned by their mother, oh.
#那個母貓不要它們啦
Yes, abandoned by the mother.
#我撿回來養
So I brought them back home.
#現在都那麼大啦
They've grown quite a lot now.
#幹嘛 叫得那麼慘
Come on! Why are you screaming so miserably?
#它不喜歡 它不喜歡我抓它
It hates ... It hates me catching it.
#喵 (註︰這應該是原字幕錯誤，村霸分明是在咆哮，不是喵)
Hm!
#不聽話
Naughty!
#喵
Meow!
#嗯 它在幹嘛
Um? What is it doing?
#在拉尿 (註︰其實他是說「痾」，不是「拉」)
Peeing.
#別拉(痾)啦
Don't pee!
#你看 這個貓
Look! This cat,
#好聽話的哦
is so nice.
#它又在那裡叫 哎喲 想咬人的那個
It's screaming again. Aiyo! It wants to bite.
#呵呵 好想 (註︰不知他想說甚麼)
Ho ho! I wanna...
#我現在喂了它一個月啦
I've been keeping them for a month already.
#一個月也這麼 那麼大啦
Just a month, and they're, they're already that big now.
#老是喜歡跑
It always wants to run away.
#過來 它不過來
Come! It's not coming.
#你看 這個 貓 在走牆角
Look! This, cat, is walking along the corner.
#別挖我牆角 (註︰其實我不知道甚麼是「挖牆角」)
Don't dig my walls!
#挖了我牆角
If you ever do it,
#把你賣掉
you'll be sold!
#抓不到它 可以看
I can't catch it. I can just watch it.
#它
It,
#只許看不許摸的
allows only watching but not touching.
#不要提它尾巴
I'd better not take its tail.
#喵
Meow!
#要不要魚吃 要不要
Do you want fish? Huh?
#自從這兩隻貓
Since I have adopted
#放到我家裡來
these two cats at my place,
#它們就 那我們家就沒有老鼠啦
they've, I've not seen any mice.
#全部被它們趕走啦
They've expelled all the mice.
#抓老鼠老它肯定怕
I don't think they dare to catch the mice.
#老鼠都比它還大
The mice are even larger than they are.
#但是可以起到恐嚇 死嚇老鼠
But they can threaten, threaten the mice.
#老鼠就不敢進我們家
Then the mice dare not come to my place.
#你看 好享受哇
Look! It enjoys so much,
#我摸一下它的脖子
when I'm touching its neck.
#舒不舒服
Is it great?
#舒服就要給錢的哦
You have to pay if you enjoy it.
#不給錢我才不給你按摩
You don't pay me. I don't serve you now.
#摸不聽話 (註︰完全不明白)
Naughty!
#你看 這個也湊熱鬧
Look! The other cat wants to join.
#你也來湊熱鬧是不是
You wanna join, don't you?
#我也抱一下你
Give you a hug.
#要不要
Do you want it?
#這樣包它才行
I need to hold in this way.
#它爪子一伸出來 它就想抓我
It's stretching out the claws. It wants to scratch me.
#應該是哦 你看 這樣提著它 它很老實誒
Yea! Look? It behaves so much better when I hold it in this way.
#動不動一下
It's like a statue.
#這樣就很舒服是不是
It's very comfortable, isn't it?
#是不是
Isn't it?
#誒呦 發 發脾氣啦
Eyo! It's, it's angry.
#好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
#我要上山砍竹子啦
I need to chop some bamboos on the hill.